The term deep learning refers to training neural networks.
深度学习中经常训练神经网络
Sometimes very large neural networks.
有时候它的规模很大
So what exactly is a neural network?
那么神经网络究竟是什么呢
In this video, let's try to give you some of the basic intuitions.
在这个视频中 会讲些直观的基础知识
Let's start with a housing price prediction example.
让我们从一个房价预测的例子开始讲起
Let's say you have a data sets with six houses.
假设你有一个六间房屋的数据集
So you know the size of the houses in square feet or
你知道房屋的面积 平方英尺
square meters, and you know the price of the house, and you want to fit
或者是平方米 以及知道房屋价格 你想要拟合
a function to predict the price of
the house as a function of the size.
一个根据房屋面积预测房价的函数
So if you are familiar with linear regression, you might say, well,
所以如果你对线性回归很熟悉 你可能会说 好吧
let's fit a straight line to this data.
让我们在这些数据上拟合一条直线
So maybe you got a straight line like that.
于是你可能会得到这样一条直线
But to be a bit fancier, you might say, well,
但有点奇怪的是 你可能也发现了
we know that prices can never be negative.
我们知道价格永远不会是负数的
So instead of a straight line fit which would eventually become negative,
因此替代一条可能会让价格为负的直线的是
let's bend the curve here so
it just ends up zero here.
让我们在这里弯曲一点让它最终在零结束
So this thick blue line ends up being your function for
这条粗的蓝线最终就是你的函数
predicting the price of a house as a function of its size.
用于根据房屋面积预测价格
Whereas, zero here and then there's a straight line fit to the right.
这里是零 而这里的直线拟合的很好
You can think of this function that you just fit to housing prices
你也许认为这个函数只拟合房屋价格
as a very simple neuro network.
作为一个非常简单的神经网络
It's almost the simplest possible neuro network.
这几乎可能是最简单的神经网络
Let me draw it here.
让我画在这里
We have as the input to the neuro network, the size of the house,
我们把房屋的面积作为神经网络的输入
which we will call x.
称之为x
It goes into this node, this little circle.
通过这个节点 这个小圆圈
And then it outputs the price we call y.
最终输出了价格 用y表示
So this little circle which is a single neuron, and
其实这个小圆圈就是一个单独的神经元
then your network implements this function that we drew on the left.
接着你的网络实现了左边这个函数的功能
And in the neuro network literature, you see this function a lot.
在有关神经网络的文献中 你经常看得到这个函数
This function which goes to zero sometime
and then takes off as a straight line.
从趋近于零开始 然后变成一条直线
This function is called a ReLU
这个函数被称作ReLu
function, which stands for
激活函数 它的全称是
rectified linear unit, so ReLU.
rectified linear unit 即ReLU
And rectify just means taking a max of zero,
rectify（修正）可以理解成取比零大的数字或零
which is why you get a function shaped like this.
这也是你得到一个这样形状的函数的原因
You don't need to worry about ReLU units for now, but
你现在不用担心不理解ReLU函数
it's just something you see again later in this course.
你将会在这门课的后面再次看到它
So if this is a single neural network,
好的 如果这是一个单神经元网络
maybe a tiny little neural network, a larger neural network
也许规模很小 也许规模很大
is then formed by taking many of these
single neurons and stacking them together.
通过把这些单个神经元叠加在一起来形成
So if you think of this neuron is being like a single Lego brick, you then
你可以把这些神经元想象成单独的乐高积木
get a bigger neural network by stacking
together many of these Lego bricks.
你通过搭积木来完成一个更大的神经网络
Let's see an example.
让我们来看一个例子
Let's say that instead of predicting
the price of a house just from its size,
我们不仅仅用房屋的面积来预测它的价格
you now have other features,
other things about the house,
现在你有了一些有关房屋的其它特征
such as the number of bedrooms,
shall we write this [INAUDIBLE] bedrooms.
比如卧室的数量
And you might think that one of the things that really affects
或许有一个很重要的因素
the price of a house is family size.
一家人的数量也会影响房屋价格
So can this house fit your family of three
or family of four, or family of five?
这个房屋能住下一个三口之家或者是四五个人的家庭吗？
And it's really based on the size in square feet or square meters, and
价格的确是基于房屋的面积
the number of bedrooms that determines whether or
和卧室的数量 不能确定的是
not a house can fit your family's family size.
一个家庭的人数是否会对房屋价格造成影响
And then maybe you know the zip codes in different
换个话题 你可能知道邮编 在别的
countries is called the postal code.
国家也被叫作邮政编码
And the zip code maybe as a feature that tells you walkability.
邮编或许能作为一个特征 告诉你步行化程度
So is this neighborhood highly walkable?
比如这附近是不是高度步行化
Can you just walk to the grocery store and then walk to school?
你是否能步行去杂货店或者是学校
Do you need to drive?
你是否需要驾驶汽车
Some people prefer highly walkable neighborhoods.
有些人喜欢居住在以步行为主的区域
And then the zip code, as well as the wealth maybe,
另外根据邮政编码 还有富裕程度
tells you, certainly in the United States.
在美国是这样的
But some other countries as well tells you how good is the school quality.
但在其它国家也可能体现出附近学校的水平有多好
So each of these little circles I'm drawing can be one of those ReLU,
这里每一个我画的小圆圈都可以是ReLU的一部分
rectified linear unit, or some other slightly nonlinear function so that based
也就是指修正线性单元 或者其它稍微非线性的函数
on the size and number of bedrooms, you can estimate the family size.
基于房屋面积和卧室数量 也可以估算家庭人口
With the zip code, estimate walkability,
基于邮编 估测步行化程度
based on zip code as well you can estimate the school quality.
基于邮编 你也可以估测学校的质量
And then, finally, you might think that,
最后你可能会这样想
well, the way people decide how much they're willing to pay for
人们决定他们乐意花费多少钱
a house is they look at the things that really matter to them.
在一个房屋上 是与这些影响他们的事情息息相关的
In this case, family size, walkability and school quality and
在这个情景里 家庭人口 步行化程度以及学校的质量
that helps you predict the price.
都能帮助你预测房屋的价格
So in this example, x is all of these four
以此为例 x是所有的这四个输入
inputs and y is the price you're trying to predict.
y 是你尝试预测的价格
And so by stacking together a few of the
single neurons or the simple predictors
把这些单个的神经元叠加在一起 或者说是我们在上一页
we had from the previous slide, we now
have a slightly larger neuro network.
幻灯片做的简单预测 我们现在有了一个稍微大一点的神经网络
It turns out that a lot of the magic of
a neuro network is that even though I had
这显示了神经网络的神奇之处 虽然我已经
described a neuro network as requiring
you to figure out that family size,
描述了一个神经网络 通过要求你得到房屋面积
walkability and school quality are the factors, or
步行化程度 学校的质量 这些是已经知道的
the things that determine a price.
还有一些其它影响价格的因素
Part of the magic of a neural network is that when you implement it,
神经网络的一部分神奇之处在于 当你实现它之后
you need to give it just the input, x.
你要做的只是输入x
And the output y, for number of examples in your training set, and
就能得到输出y 在你训练集的许多样本里
all these things in the middle it will figure out by itself.
所有的中间过程都是它自己完成的
So what you actually implement is this,
那么你实际上做的就是
where here you have a neural networks with four inputs.
这儿你有了包括四个输入的神经网络
So the input the features might be the size number of bedrooms,
因此输入的特征可能是卧室的数量
the zip code or postal codes, and the wealth of the neighborhood.
邮政编码 和区域的富裕程度
And so given these input features,
给出这些输入的特征
the job of the neural network will be to predict the price.
神经网络的工作就是预测对应的价格
And notice also that each of these circles, these are called hidden units
同时也注意到这些圆圈 这些被叫做隐藏单元
in a neural network, that each of them takes its input of four input features.
在一个神经网络中 它们每个都从输入的四个特征获得自身输入
So for example, rather than saying this first nodes represents family size and
比如说 第一个结点代表家庭人口
family size depends only on the features
x1 and x2, instead, we're going to say,
而家庭人口仅仅取决于x1和x2特征 换句话说
well, neural network, you decide whatever you want this node to be and
在神经网络中 你决定在这个结点中想要得到什么
we'll give you all four input features to compute whatever you want.
我们给出所有的四个输入来计算想要得到的
So we say that the layers is this input layer and
因此我们说这一层输入层 以及
this layer in the middle, the neural network, are densely connected
在中间的这一层 在神经网络中被紧密的连接起来了
because every input feature's connected to everyone of these circles in the middle.
因为输入的每一个特征都连接到了中间的这些圆圈
And the remarkable thing about neural networks is that given enough data about x
值得注意的是神经网络给予了足够的数据 有关x
and y, given enough training examples with both x and y, neural networks
和y 给予了足够的训练样本有关x和y 神经网络
are remarkably good at figuring out functions that accurately map from x to y.
非常擅长计算从x到y的精准映射函数
So that's a basic neural network.
这就是一个基础的神经网络
It turns out that as you build out your own neural networks you probably find them
你可能发现你自己的神经网络
to be most useful, most powerful, in supervised learning settings.
在监督学习的环境下是如此的有效和强大
Meaning that you're trying to take an input x and
也就是说你只要尝试输入一个X
map it some output y, like we just saw
in the housing price prediction example.
即可把它映射成y 就好像我们在刚才房价预测的例子中看到的
In the next video, let's go over some more examples
of supervised learning, and
在下一个视频中 让我们复习一下更多监督学习的例子
some examples of where you might find your
networks to be incredibly helpful for
有些例子会让你觉得你的网络会十分有用
your applications, as well.
你实际应用起来也是如此